Claude Code 拥有用于读取和编辑 Jupyter notebooks 的工具。
Claude Code has tools for reading and editing Jupyter notebooks.
在本节课中，我们将通过
In this lesson, we'll go through
第二个示例，学习如何使用 Claude Code
our second example and use Claude Code
来重构 Jupyter notebook 并将其转换为仪表盘。
to refactor a Jupyter notebook and transform it into a dashboard.
让我们开始吧。到目前为止我们已经
Let's get to it. So far we've
看到了如何使用 Claude Code 来
seen how to use Claude Code to
处理前端和后端的 Web 应用程序。
work with web applications on the front end and back end.
现在让我们换个方向，展示如何
Now let's shift gears and showcase how to
使用 Claude Code 来处理 Jupyter notebook。
use Claude Code to work with a Jupyter notebook.
我这里有一个 Jupyter notebook
I have a Jupyter notebook here
包含了一些虚构的电子商务数据。
with some e-commerce data that is fictitious.
这些电子商务数据是从几个 CSV 文件中
This ecommerce data is reading information from a few CSVs
读取的信息，它们就在 ecommerce_data 文件夹里。
that I have in this ecommerce_data folder.
我正在使用 pandas 读取 CSV 数据。
I'm using pandas to read data from the CSV.
我在这里展示了一些信息，读取了其他 CSV，
I'm displaying some information here, reading some other CSVs,
如你所见，
and as you can see here,
我得到了我想要的答案，
I'm getting the answers that I want,
但这些数据组织得并不理想。
but this data is not really the most organized.
我得到了一些统计信息，
I'm getting some statistical information,
但格式和展示效果可能不是
but the formatting and the display might not
我开箱即用的理想状态。
be what I'd like out of the box.
随着我继续深入并
As I go through and take a
查看更多此类信息。
look at some more of this information.
我开始意识到我正在进行一些更
I can start to see that I'm beginning to do some more
复杂的操作。我希望
complicated procedures here. One of the things that I'd
从这些数据中获得
like to get out of this data
一些见解，比如我们的
are some insights around things like how
年同比收入增长情况。
much revenue did we generate year over year.
具体来说，是 2023 年与 2022 年的对比。
Specifically, 2023 to 2022.
我这里有实现目标所需的
I have the necessary operations here
必要操作。事实上，在两个不同的
to do what I want. In fact, there's a little
CSV 和数据帧之间进行了一些合并。
bit of merging between two different CSVs and data frames.
我正在朝着想要的答案努力，
And here, I'm working my way towards the answer that I want,
但我在这里看到了一些警告。
but there are some warnings that I'm seeing here.
同时，仅仅为了直观展示
at the same time, it takes a while just to show visually
我想要的内容及其最佳显示方式，就花费了很长时间。
what I want and how best to display it.
虽然我最终得到了想要的数字，
So while I do end up getting the numbers that I want,
但这有点枯燥且凌乱。我
it's a little bit tedious and messy. I
想要一种更好的方式来展示这些信息
want a way to better showcase this information
并探索如何重构这个 Jupyter notebook。
and I want to explore how I can refactor this Jupyter notebook.
正如我们在其他部分看到的那样，
As we see in a few other sections,
我正试图计算一些高层指标，如平均订单价值
I'm trying to calculate some high level metrics like average order values
我不只是想要
and not only am I looking for
这个数字，而且这只是 2023 年的数据。
this number, but this is just for 2023.
如果我想要 2024 年甚至以后的数据该怎么办？
What happens when I want 2024 and so on.
当我们向下滚动时，我们会看到一些
As we scroll down, we'll see some visualizations
还不错的可视化效果。但我认为我们可以做得更好。
that are pretty good. But I think we could do better.
当我们快到
As we work our way towards the
底部时，我们仍在计算更多这些
bottom, we're still calculating more of these
高层数值，如按州划分的销售额。
high level values like sales by state.
我们再次生成了一些可视化效果，但我认为
We're generating some visualizations again, but I think we could do
在使用 Claude Code 等工具后，我们可以做得更好。
much better as we start to use tools like Claude Code.
考虑到这一点，让我们
So with that in mind, let's
展示如何使用 Claude Code
showcase how we can use Claude Code
来重构这个 notebook 并更好地
to refactor this notebook and better
将业务逻辑与展示逻辑分离。
consolidate our business logic from our presentation.
我要打开 Claude，并
So I'm going to go ahead and open up Claude, and
输入一个提示词，
I'm going to put in a prompt that I have here
其中引用了该 notebook 以及我正在处理的
that references the notebook as well as the other files that
其他文件。我将
that I'm working with. I'm going to
粘贴这个提示词。
go ahead and paste in this prompt.
然后我想要谈谈
And then I want to talk a
这里到底发生了什么。
little bit about what's actually happening here.
在粘贴提示词之前，
So before I paste in this prompt,
我实际上要新建一个 Markdown 文件
I'm actually going to make a new markdown file
只是为了展示它的样子，并
just to showcase what this looks like and
解释我们为什么要这样做。
walk through why we've done what we're doing here.
注意看这里，我使用这个符号引用了文件名，
Notice here, I'm referencing the name of the file using this sign,
也以同样的方式引用了文件夹名。
as well as the name of the folder using this as well.
如果你不确定如何最好地编写提示词
If you're ever unsure of how best to prompt
或如何要求 Claude 执行任务，
or how best to ask Claude for what to do,
你也可以直接问 Claude。很多
you can always ask Claude as well. So many
时候，我发现自己在使用 Claude AI
times, I find myself using tools like Claude AI
甚至 Claude Code 时，会直接问
or even Claude Code and just asking
Claude：我想做这件事，
Claude, here's what I want to do,
请给我一个完成此任务的最佳提示词。
give me the best possible prompt to accomplish this task.
在我们的案例中，我们对
In our case, we have some Refactoring Requirements
布局结构有一些重构要求。
for how we want the structure to be laid out.
我们对特定的 Python 文件有一些代码质量改进
We have Code Quality Improvements and some asks that we have
和要求。
for particular Python files that we want.
我们要求 Claude 在这里
What we're asking Claude to do
创建一个独立的 Python 文件
here is create a separate Python file
用于加载和处理数据。
for loading our data and processing it.
然后再创建另一个 Python 文件用于计算这些指标。
And then another Python file for calculating these metrics.
这种关注点分离将使我们能够更好地测试
This separation of concerns is going to allow us to better test
并理解支撑我们在重构后的 notebook 中
and better understand what the code is that's powering
创建的可视化效果的代码。
these visualizations that we make in our refactored notebook.
我们还要求改进可视化效果。
We're also asking for improved visualizations.
我们在这里更加
We're being a little bit more
具体地说明了我们的要求。
specific with what we mean by that.
最后，我们希望对
Finally, we want to have a little bit
正在处理的数据进行更多的配置。
more configuration around the data that we're working with.
一般来说，让
In general, it's a good practice to
Claude 知道你的预期是一个好习惯。
let Claude know what you're expecting here.
所以不要只说“重构这个”，而是说“给我一个
So instead of just refactor this, give me
重构后的 notebook 的底层资源。”
underlying asset for a refactored notebook.
给我一种记录
Give me a way to document
函数和计算业务指标的方法。
my functions and calculate my business metrics.
然后再给我一些用于处理依赖关系的重要文件，
and then give me some other important files for the dependencies I'm
以及一份说明如何使用它的 README。
working on, as well as a README explaining how to use this.
让我们复制并粘贴进去。
So let's go ahead and copy this and paste it in.
你会注意到，粘贴一定数量的
And you'll notice that after you paste a certain number
行后，Claude Code 不会显示所有内容。
of lines, Claude Code is not going to show you everything.
为了保持终端简洁。
to keep things a little bit more concise in the terminal.
让我们运行这个提示词。
So let's go ahead and run this prompt.
就像我们使用其他工具一样，
As we've done with other kinds of tools,
我们在这里将使用稍微不同的工具集。
we're going to be using a slightly different suite of tooling here.
我们不只是读取，而是处理 notebook 读取。
instead of reading, we're going to be dealing with notebook reading.
但我们之前看到的
But the same to-do list that we
待办清单将像往常一样
saw before, it's going to be executed
通过 Claude Code 执行。
just like we've gotten very accustomed to with Claude Code.
这里我们使用了 read notebook。
Here we're using that read notebook.
我们将探索那些单元格，分析结构
We're going to explore those cells, we're going to analyze the structure
并创建我们期望的重构后的 notebook。
and create the refactored notebook that we expect.
完成后，我们应该能够
Once this is done, we should expect
看到强大的可视化效果，
to see not only some powerful visualizations,
还有一些包含助手函数的文件，
but also some other files with helper functions
用于加载数据、处理数据，
for loading data, processing data,
以及计算我们需要的业务指标。
and calculating the business metrics that we need.
接受对这些 Python 文件的更改，
accept the changes to these Python files
我们会看到 Python 代码正在
and we'll see that Python is being
通过正确的工具为我们编写。
written for us using the right tool.
然后我们将编写另一个包含指标计算的 Python 文件，
We'll then go ahead and write another Python file with metric calculations
用于最终的数据和展示。
for our eventual data and display. As
随着 Claude Code 完成这些独立任务，
Claude Code is working through these individual tasks,
我们可以随时检查已创建的文件。
we can always examine the files that have been created.
我们可以看一眼，
We can give that a look and
开箱即用的
we can see right out of the box
这种面向对象的方法比
this kind of object-oriented approach is much cleaner than
将所有内容直接嵌入到我们的 notebook 中要整洁得多。
trying to embed everything directly inside of our notebook.
业务指标计算也是如此。
We can see the same thing for our business metrics calculation.
我们可以看到计算能力、传入
and we can see here, the ability to calculate, passing
数据帧并返回可视化效果以及对数据的验证。
in data frames and returning visualizations and validation of that data.
看来我们已经创建了业务指标，
Looks like we've created our business metrics,
最后是 notebook、requirements.txt，很快还会有 README。
and finally, our notebook, our requirements.txt, and soon to be our README.
在运行的同时，让我们
So while this is running, let's
看看重构后的 notebook。
take a look at the refactored notebook.
让我们确保可以
Let's go ahead and make sure we can run
按预期运行所有单元格。
all of these cells as expected.
从视觉上看，这马上
Right off the bat, this is
就显得好多了。
looking a bit nicer visually for us.
我看到它试图读取
I see here that it's trying to read
提示词，我会告诉 Claude：
the prompt, and I'll just let Claude know,
不需要读取提示词，直接完成 README 即可。
no need to read the prompt, just finish making the README.
当我查看这个 notebook 时，我
As I take a look at this notebook, I can
发现它好得多了。
see right out of the box, this is much, much nicer.
我得到了对正在查看的数据的分析，
I'm getting analysis into what data I'm looking at,
还有一些可以操作的配置。
and also some configuration to work with.
我可以指定年份和对比数据，
I can specify the years and comparison data
甚至可以指定月份。
and even any month if I want as well.
我将在整个 notebook 中使用这些常量。
I'll be using these constants across the notebook.
这里我可以看到所需的数据加载，
Here I can see the data loading that's required
这些是我类中的自定义模块。
here are the custom modules that I have from my classes.
所以，当我运行所有单元格时，
So, as I'm running all of these cells,
到目前为止看起来都很棒。
looks like things are pretty good so far.
但如果我再往下滚一点，实际上会看到
But if I scroll down a little bit more, I'll actually see
这里有一个错误。我一眼就能
that there's an error here. I can see right
看出问题似乎是
off the bat, the problem here appears to be
某种 key error。所以我要
some kind of key error. So I'm going
让 Claude 帮我修复。
to ask Claude to fix that for me.
我会说：我正在得到 KeyError
I'll say I'm getting KeyError
运行特定单元格时。我本可以
when I run a particular cell. I could
尝试让 Claude Code 帮我找出来，
try to have Claude Code figure that out for me,
但我实际上会把
but I'm actually going to give Claude Code
我运行的代码给它，这样
the code that I used so that
它就有更多的上下文。
it has a little bit more context.
Claude Code 将
Claude Code is going to take a
查看需要执行的操作。
look at what needs to be done.
找出问题所在并为我们进行更改。
see what the issue is and make the change for us.
好了，现在更改已经做好了，让我们
All right, let's go ahead and run these
运行这些单元格。
cells now that this changes have been made.
让我们确保情况变好了一些。
And let's go make sure that things are looking a bit better.
如你所见，当我向下滚动时，
You can see here as I scroll down,
不再看到之前的错误了。
I'm not seeing those errors that I was before.
现在让我们看看它
And now let's take a look at some
返回给我的一些业务指标。
of the business metrics that it's returning to me.
得到了更漂亮的摘要展示、关于客户满意度的信息，
Getting nicer displays of summaries, information on customer satisfaction,
这比我之前拥有的
that's a little bit easier to
要容易处理得多。
work with than what I had before.
当我们转向收入分析时，
As we shift gears towards our revenue analysis,
我们可以开始看到更清晰的数值、展示了更多信息，
we can start to see clearer values, more displayed information
并进行了一些工作，
and a little bit of work to
以更轻松地展示数据，
more easily display the data we're working
可视化效果看起来也更赏心悦目了。
with the visualizations appear to be more pleasant looking.
当我们查看类别表现时，
we can see as we look at category performance,
我们有了更好的工具来
we've got some even better tools to
分析类别及与之相关的收入。
analyze categories and revenue associated with them.
查看地理表现时，
As we look at our geographic performance,
我们看到了按州划分的漂亮可视化效果。
we're seeing a nice visualization by state.
我们可以将鼠标悬停在上面，
We can hover over that to get
以获取各州更详细的信息。
even more information on a state-by-state basis.
当我们进行到最后，
As we work our way to the bottom,
查看额外的交付分析时，
when we take a look at additional delivery analysis,
一切都如预期般顺利。
things are looking good as expected.
我们在重构这个 notebook、
So we've done a nice job refactoring this notebook
实现更直观的数据展示以及分离关注点方面做得很好。
to more visually display information and separate our concerns.
但我现在想做的是：
But what I'd like to do now is
从 notebook 迁移到基于 Web 的界面，
move from a notebook to a web-based interface
使用 Streamlit 构建一个精美的仪表盘。
with a nice dashboard powered by Streamlit.
如果你不熟悉 Streamlit，它是一个 Python 库，
If you're not familiar with Streamlit, it's a Python library
用于展示界面，特别是仪表盘，
that's useful for displaying interfaces, particularly dashboards,
非常易于使用，可以无缝地
and it's very easy to seamlessly transition
从 notebook 转换为这些 Python 文件。
from notebooks to these Python files.
让我们新建一个
So let's go ahead and make
名为 convert-to-dashboard.md 的 Markdown 文件
a new markdown file with our prompt
作为我们的提示词。
that we'll call convert-to-dashboard.md
让我们看看要在
And let's walk through what we're going to
里面放什么。我们要要求 Claude
put in here. We're going to ask Claude
将我们的重构后的 notebook 转换为一个专业的
to convert our refactored notebook into a professional
Streamlit 仪表盘，并采用精确的布局。
professional Streamlit dashboard with this exact layout.
我们可以只从第一行开始，
We could start just with this first line,
但为了避免来回
but in order to avoid lots of back
沟通，直接告诉 Claude 我们想要什么。
and forth, let's just tell Claude what we want.
我们需要一个带有标题和过滤器的页眉；
We want a header with a title and filter,
需要带有收入、
we want KPIs with cards for revenue,
增长、平均订单价值和总
growth, toward average order value and total
订单卡片的 KPI。然后我们需要一些图表。
orders. And then we want some charts.
收入、类别、按州划分的收入，以及一个显示满意度的条形图。
revenue, categories, revenue by state, and a bar chart with satisfaction.
在底层，我们需要两个卡片，
At the bottom row, we want two cards,
并且我们要明确指定
and we want to be specific for the way
数据展示和渲染信息的方式。
in which we display our data and render this information.
考虑到这一点，让我们
So with that in mind, let's
试一试。
go ahead and give this a shot.
让我们利用 Streamlit 从 notebook 迁移到可视化界面。
Let's migrate from notebooks to visual interfaces using Streamlit.
我们可以看到它已经创建了我们的仪表盘，
We can see that it's created our dashboard,
在它运行的同时，我们可以
and as it's going, we can take
看看这里做了什么。
a look at what's being done here.
我们正在导入 Streamlit，引入 pandas，
We're importing Streamlit, bringing in pandas,
引入包括 Plotly 在内的可视化工具。
bringing in some visualizations including Plotly.
在这里你可以看到我们正在展示用于
And then here you can see we're displaying some custom CSS for
样式设置的自定义 CSS，设置我们的页面配置。
styling, setting up our page configuration.
大部分内容实际上来自那个
Most of this really comes from that st
我用来操作 Streamlit 的 st 对象。我们更新了 requirements。
object that I have to work with Streamlit. We've updated our requirements.
txt，在这里我们实际上要创建一个 README
txt, and here we're actually going to create a README
展示仪表盘中所有情况的 README。
displaying everything that's going on in the dashboard.
事实上，我现在会告诉 Claude：
In fact, I'll just tell Claude right now,
不要创建新的 README，只需修改现有的即可。
don't make a new README, just modify the one we have.
在许多这种较长的计划中，
In many of these longer plans, it's
很容易就让 Claude 自己跑，
very easy to just let Claude go,
但有时你想停止进程，
but sometimes you want to stop the process
让它按照你想要的方式
and have it navigate the way that
运行。既然我们已经创建了这个仪表盘，
you want. Now that we've created this dashboard,
让我们打开一个新的终端窗口来启动服务器。
let's open up a new terminal window to start our server.
在左侧的终端窗口中，我将使用以下命令启动服务器：
In this terminal window on the left, I'll start the server using
streamlit run 然后是即将被
streamlit run and then the Python file that's going to be
显示的 Python 文件 dashboard.py。我们可以看到
displayed dashboard.py. We can see here
我这里还没有 streamlit 命令。
that I don't have the Streamlit command.
所以我意识到，为了
So I can see here, in
让一切运行起来，
order to get everything up and running,
我需要安装这些依赖项。
I need to install these dependencies.
那我们就开始做吧。
So let's go ahead and do that.
我将运行 pip install 命令，
I'll run my pip install command,
安装所有必要的依赖项，并确保
install all the necessary dependencies and make sure
在服务器加载时，应用程序中的
that when the server loads, I don't have
依赖项不会出现任何问题。
any issues with the dependencies in this application.
完成后，我将启动服务器。
Once that's done, I'll go ahead and run my server.
我将使用 streamlit run 命令来启动。
And I'll do that using the streamlit run command.
让我们输入 streamlit
So let's go ahead and type in streamlit
run 以及我们 Python 文件的名称。
run and the name of our Python file.
就像它在这里建议的一样。
Python file just like it suggests right here.
回到浏览器，这就是现在的样子。
Back in the browser, here's what things look like.
我得到了一些收入，一些增长。
I've got some revenue, I've got some growth.
当我们稍微往下滚一点时，
As we scroll down a little bit,
我们肯定要验证一下
we're definitely going to want to verify
这些数字是否符合我们的预期。
that these numbers are what we expect.
我们看到有些东西还缺了一点。
And we see that some things are still missing a little bit.
当我们查看这个
When we take a look at this
仪表盘时，这是一个好的开始，但我们
dashboard, it's a pretty good start, but we
可以发现还缺少几样东西。
can see that we're missing a couple things.
看起来这些卡片是空的，
It looks like these cards here are empty
实际上也是多余的，因为我们已经得到了想要的信息。
and actually redundant because we're getting the information that we want.
同时，从 2024 年开始显示有点困难。
At the same time, it's a little difficult to start with 2024.
因为我们看不到太多的年同比信息。
because we're not seeing much information year over year.
所以也许我们应该要求 Claude
So maybe we should ask Claude
不仅清理这些部分，
to not only clean up these pieces,
还要将默认年份设为 2023 年，
but also start with a default year of 2023,
这样我们可以看到一些稍微漂亮的可视化效果。
so we can have some slightly nicer visualizations.
同时确保我们有能力
but also make sure we have the ability
基于月份进行过滤。
to filter based on the month as well.
我们想要从 2023 年开始的原因是，
The reason why we'll want to start with 2023
我们还没有 2024 年每个月的数据。
is because we don't have data for every single month for 2024.
所以当我们开始查看时，
So as we start to look at
月度增长是
this, the monthly growth is
有点令人困惑的。
a little bit confusing.
而这里的数据，我们还没有得到。
And the data here, we just don't have yet.
所以让我们提出这些要求，把它们传回给 Claude。
So let's go make those asks, put them back in Claude.
这是一个好的开始，但我想要
This is a good start, but I want to
实施以下更改：
implement the following changes.
让我们在这里
Let's go ahead and make a
另起一行，首先我们要
new line here and first we'll start
确保默认年份是 2023 年。
with making sure the default year is 2023.
接下来，要求 Claude 也添加按月份过滤的功能。
Next, ask Claude to add filters for months as well.
最后，我们要确保
And then finally, we'll make sure
移除每个空的卡片。
to remove the empty card for each.
好，让我们在仪表盘中为这些特定任务更新代码。
So, let's update the code in our dashboard for these particular tasks.
我们将默认年份设置为 2023 年，这看起来不错。
We'll set the default year to 2023, which looks good.
在这里我们添加了一些月份过滤器。
And here we'll add some filters for months.
现在让我们更新收入图表，以处理
Now let's update the revenue chart to handle
按特定月份过滤的情况。
the case where we're filtering by a specific month.
我们可以看到 CSS 也在发生变化。
We can see the CSS is changing as well.
所以看起来这个图表容器
So it looks like this chart container
应该比以前更整洁了。
should be a little bit cleaner than before.
让我们回到浏览器，看看情况。
Let's go back to the browser, see what things look like.
我们可以看到 2023 年是
We can see that 2023 is
默认设置，这是一个好的开始。
the default, which is a good start.
我们还可以看到那些
We can also see that those
空的卡片已经不在了，这太棒了。
empty cards are gone, which is great.
我们现在先停在这里，但你可以想象随着你不断
We'll stop here for now, but you can imagine as you keep
通过提示词引导，你可以创建更强大的可视化效果。
prompting, you can create more powerful visualizations.
但在很短的时间内，我们从一个
But in a short period of time, we started with a notebook
有点混乱、
that was a bit disorganized,
难以阅读和理解的 notebook。
was a little hard to read and understand.
迁移到了一个我们可以部署、
And we migrated now to a dashboard that we can deploy,
与团队成员分享并快速迭代的仪表盘。
share with team members and iterate on quickly.
在下一节课中，我们将构建一个 Next.js 应用程序，
In the next lesson, we'll build a Next.js application
并使用 Claude Code 连接到 MCP 服务器，
and use Claude Code to connect to MCP servers
用于 Figma 和 Playwright，从而利用原型图构建一个
for Figma and Playwright to take a mockup and build a
利用 Claude Code 快速构建强大的 Web 应用程序。
powerful web application with Claude Code quickly.